good evening everyone and again a warm
welcome to all the delegates uh for this
uh important uh session that we are
going to have on
insurance uh I think insurance has been
one of the key spokes into uh auto
dealership and overall insurance if I
look at motor insurance in India it is
contributing to almost 1
trillion uh Indian rupees uh in terms of
its Market size and uh growing at almost
11 to 12% on an cagr basis expected to
reach 2 trillion by
2029 contributing to almost 1/3 of the
non-life insurance Market in the country
today I'm sure it has its own importance
with the insurance companies as well
while uh this is there it is also
plagued by a lot of though it is always
known to be a loss making uh business
for them but Health also contributes
equally into this uh business of
insurance
companies for us dealers this has been
one of the uh key Revenue sources and uh
an important component both in sales and
at Service as well so again uh I want to
extend a warm welcome to all the
panelists just to uh to set the tone
here I'll like to
understand how
uh we see this business from the
insurance end and how do they relate to
it uh as as a partnership with the
dealers let me start with Mr mea uh your
views on this
business yeah thank you um if you really
look at uh the insurance ecosystem um I
think this cannot flourish if if there
is no intermediation and uh when we look
at intermediation the key intermediary
channel is actually the dealership
business or the misp business today and
uh I think the entire uh you know uh the
entire universe around vehicles uh has
three elements to it one the customer
who's buying the vehicle the dealer
who's selling it and obviously the
insurance uh company which is basically
giving the cover and uh be it the
policies and the remuneration there on
or the after sales uh related to you
know accidental repairs uh replacement
so on and so forth even that is a
revenue channel for the dealership so I
think this entire ecosystem is well
oiled and while we do see some amount of
frictions but I think the transformation
uh in today's time is more towards how
do we get more customers retained uh in
the dealership Channel how do we ensure
the customer loyalty to continue with
the insurance company and the dealer
partner and what should be done uh as a
plus one which a customer uh you know
sees as a unique proposition when he
looks at a dealership and an insurance
company in combination I think that's
where the product line has to
continuously keep getting expanded so
from a vanilla Insurance product you've
already moved to products which
basically cover 100% depreciation return
to invoice things like that you are
going to the next level where you're
also looking at some amount of
accidental and hospitalization products
getting attached to motor policies U
that is on the retention side then
obviously bettering of the price uh end
price to the customer Without Really
compromising on the dealer remuneration
uh how do you select a customer which
can yield better returns more from an
insurance standpoint and also from the
dealer point I think this entire um uh
Universe I would say requires constant
monitoring and very very high level of
communication both sides and obviously
uh overarching to all of this is the OEM
misp programs and those program managers
who actually are the Catalyst in this
getting this entire piece together so so
these are my opening views thank you
thank you Rohit I'd like to get your
views also on
this thanks RI I think motor insurance I
think each one of his aware is the most
critical component uh product category
for The General insurance company uh but
I think one thing which we all need to
understand is industri product category
is evolving very fast these days it's
always used to be an asset based pricing
product uh we used to price maruti Swift
Honda City Etc uh the industry is
changing and if you look at from the
regulator perspective also I think
they're making lot of regulat changes
and it's becoming more of an individual
how Ro is driving how a is driving maybe
the same vehicle uh the risk is very
different and and hence we need to keep
that in mind uh that it is a very
evolving Dy DC product category in this
industry and it will continue to be a
very dominant product category in the
industry coming specifically to the
dealership as the distribution arm for
insurance company it's a very critical
role and that's one of the reason why
the regulator has made this channel a a
regulatory channel to sell insurance
right u i see this uh Channel not only
contribute uh significantly for the
motor but in the coming years it will
all start contributing on the other
lines of product also because the
customers first come to you buy a
vehicle and then they buy a motor
insurance right and you have a primary
ownership with the customer and hence
your ability to know the needs of the
customer and sell other products will be
continue to be very
relevant thank you Rohit so mvi taking
to what Mr Rohit said on how uh dealers
can be in the Channel with the dealers
though the misp dictates only the
products that we are selling uh but in
case now we want to you know do any
cross- selling for example uh household
insurance or health Atul also mentioned
about hospitalization and other policies
or even personal accident policies like
this so how do you see this evolving and
how uh the insurance companies are
looking at this partnership to take it
there uh thank you shik and good evening
to all of you uh when we see the
automotive sector in fact it constitutes
almost 7% of her GDP and it's a growing
sector now uh many of the dealers are uh
MPS and otherwise also they are into
Insurance in a big way now if you see
from the insurance point of view uh even
today 56% of her Motor Vehicles are
uninsured uh that is the data so there
are there's a lot of scope for insurance
going forward and this is a growing
industry you would have seen how I is
coming out with I regulations and so
there is tremendous scope in insurance
and you being uh there out there with a
large base of clientele in fact uh the
uh I I would say that you are one of the
uh intermediaries with the largest
client base so there is tremendous scope
for improvement and like you were saying
uh we do have so many products if you
look at all the general insurance
companies we do have more than than 200
plus products out there which uh you can
always sell to your clientele now uh as
far as the regulations are concerned
right now misp can sell only Motor
Products but going forward we do not
know a lot of changes are coming in the
sector and there are other intermediary
channels as well which you can uh look
out for so I would say that there is a
tremendous scope for cross selling of
all the products out there and as you
said uh home insurance then if you see
like some natural calamities happening
across now the protection Gap is also
almost
83% so when I say that it means when a
natural Calamity happens like a flood or
something that we have seen a lot
happening last year almost 83% of those
damaged vehicles are uninsured that is
something seriously which we have to
think about so I believe that there is
tremendous scope out there so you mean
to say that uh the enforcement and reach
has to improve definitely but don't you
think that should be uh no doubt uh as
dealers dealer Partners we will ensure
to reach out more but how do you think
uh the the insurance companies or as a
whole uh we use this country's
Administration to help us in getting
that what are you views of because uh as
an insurance company we are definitely
with you uh because we do have the uh
reach for all the these products and we
can always bundle up some products for
you which can be e uh you know very
easily sold to the customers and uh when
I see a dealer the customers always come
in you know you are slightly different
from other intermediaries wherein you
know if I talk about an agent the moment
he sells a policy then maybe he would
see that same uh client when a claim
comes or during the next renewal but in
your case it is totally different they
keep keep coming back to you either for
service of the cars or for any other for
new products or new add-on value add-ons
or new accessories so you are always in
touch with your clientele so definitely
I feel as an insurers we can definitely
come out with more bundle uh package
policies something that will help the
clients thank you ma'am uh becauseas on
taking this further to what ma'am said
uh you be being a broker as well yes
don't you think that uh Brokers like you
can engage with dealers and get these
products Till There is a regulation
coming in from uh the uh from irda could
you be in a position to offer our dealer
Partners solutions that can enhance
cross
selling yeah thank you shavei and uh
good evening everybody uh before I
answer the question uh I thank fada in
uh organizing this event in which uh it
has been there from past uh few years
now and a very structured event in which
insurance and finance is actually spoken
about so uh it is a very good
opportunity for everybody to understand
how things have been and how things are
going to shape up in future so uh now I
come to your question uh sharik so uh if
you see the past in fact uh the way
things have come up regulator has
actually opened up so many things it is
they are not limited only to one or the
other line of business so what's
happening is currently misp is supposed
to sell only motor insurance but if you
go ahead and see things would be really
different going ahead now if you talk
about how as a broker I'm going to add
value to that yes as a broker I
represent customers to insurance
companies that means I am on customer
side so what happens here is when I talk
to dealers I have to find out what are
the what are the
requirements which a customer has and at
the same time what are the opportunities
which he's missing on so now when we
have a discussion with dealer and since
the trust is there customers trust is
there on the dealership dealership has
invested crores to set up that uh since
Madam also said some time back that you
know that renewals happen at dealership
now in that kind of situation what
happens here is we come out with a lot
of products we talk to insurance
companies integrate those products in
our system so that it becomes easy for a
dealership to sell it to the customers
now when customer is already there you
have a training to your team and the
system is there to take care of uh the
products and the services and everything
is aligned it becomes a smooth process
in which insurance penetration as the
way government wants it
increases thank you thank youas another
uh big uh concern for dealers is the red
you know reducing margins that we are
making uh
and uh this is affected by a lot of
intermediates also playing uh their role
into this business where eventually they
are given better margins and more
discounts while they Prosper we are
losing to them uh Rohit how do you see
misp getting exclusivity into uh a
business like
this uh shaik G I think MP is getting
exclusivity I don't think Indian market
is today in the was in a position where
any one distribution arm would be given
a monopoly right to sell a product uh
but if you look at it today practically
for All Purpose uh in the new vehicles
you have a monopoly itself right U 95%
plus of the vehicles are insured by
dealerships only for the new vehicle uh
I don't say uh any point of time it
becoming a monopoly channel for motor
insurance but it will be the most
dominant channel for motor insurance if
you look at and just go back to what has
happened happening preo right uh the
focus of a dealerships on the old
vehicles and the retentions was very
poor right and the covid and the
lockdown taught us that how important it
is to retain the customers when the new
vehicle sales were almost zero right and
then if you look at the journey after
the covid till now we have seen the uh
dealership channels retention rates have
significantly improved that means the
other channels are reducing every year
on year right and hence We Believe uh if
we start focusing and keeping customer
in mind right that we have to retain the
customer as as man was saying that the
customer keeps coming to you multiple
times right and if the customer has
taken insurance from you uh you're
assured of he coming to you for service
he you are assured that forays he will
keep coming to you and then we have to
start looking Insurance in a very
different way that it's also a way a
medium to ensure that the customer
sticks with you and hence if they start
looking it from that perspective and uh
start working on ensuring the customer
is protected and renewed and it
continues to be with the dealership
channels I think the regulatory you will
never be the Monopoly but yeah you will
be so dominant that uh like new you can
be the old uh sud sudo Monopoly you can
run well said roit Thank you taking this
forward uh Mr thari I would uh like to
understand uh repairs are always
considered to be a little higher cost
cost at
dealerships uh and so is the tat how uh
do you suggest uh tools or processes or
equipments that can help us improve our
efficiencies improve our margins in uh
in our
workshops thank you Mr sha
uh I come from the equipment background
and U repl repair not replace has been
our mantra for quite some time uh a lot
of progress has been made in this
category uh especially uh if you look at
a body shop uh almost 65 to 70% of the
workload in Body Shop comes from the
smaller repairs okay they are not full
vle crash there are Insurance claim but
then they are smaller in nature uh we
have been able to work can get uh
equipments we call them as a PDR you
know paintless dent removal system uh
little bit skill one requires but I'm
pretty sure with the kind of Manpower
that is available in the dealership if
one is focused little bit on the
training on them one can use these tools
to bring productivity and also at the
same time reduce the cost because it
it's clearly a tool that can do good
amount of work without disturbing the
paint in the
system uh we have been working on this
and uh it it's been uh let's say uh it's
still a long way to go to get acceptance
across the various oems but it's still
certainly a tool globally that is used
uh to improve the productivity in the
workshop especially in the smaller job
area which is the majority of the load
in the
workshop uh thank you so I think Mr
tiari is wanting Mr sah you to be out of
business uh if if he doesn't want to get
the vehicles repaired without any pain
your views also on how uh you know
eventually when the car is delivered and
if it's a proper painted car and that's
where you know the skill and also the
infrastructure makes and that all out
dealers have what is your views on this
point okay thanks thanks sharck and good
evening ladies and gentlemen so I
contribute to automotive repair industry
from a automotive quoting paint supplier
point of view and as one of the
stakeholder where OEM is there where
repairer U is there uh and then
obviously insurance company is there and
we are there contributing arbit you know
uh one thing in the past say 25 30 year
of landscape in India we have seen that
though we are you know one of the
stakeholder in this ecosystem but there
a lot of push and pull happens amongst
us where we actually talk all the
customer Cent City because actually
customer is one but whom he
belongs plus the way this industry have
matured in past 25 30 year today you
mentioned 85% contribute you know paid
by Insurance 60% is a small repair still
you know two three panel jobs are
getting paid by Insurance Company
are we matur to handle those repairs
effectively efficiently and before that
you know it's not just about you know
repairing it or painting it the customer
pain starts while the time he comes to a
shop and estimation starts so we always
say key to key time since he gives the
key for estimation and come back after
getting repaired so while we as a
stakeholder we always feel that proper
efficiency in terms of tools and
equipment training skill sets of a
technician everything play a role
however is still what in India if we
compare with a matured market and our
origination we see labor time estimation
is actually not there and lot many time
when we as a stakeholder connect in an
individual basis everybody is putting
their interest first to kill other
one so that is where when the customer
is same stakeholders are evolved around
the same customer if we tend to kill
each other just by not looking overall
efficiency which impacts the
profitability heavily you know it's like
doggy dog and then it becomes nonviable
day by day for a lot of people people
you know voices these pain in
isolation so again as as when when I
speak to a lot of people you know it's
like you being in a European union and
different people is speaking different
language ultimately you know we are
trying to feel that okay customer is
going to speak all four language which
we are speaking individually so key to
key time will going to be ke uh key play
uh digitalized estimation is I see a
biggest thing though lot of you know uh
bottlenecks are there but that's very
very important why it's important
because if you look a average dealership
a average shop which repair say 200 250
cars in a month in a 25 working day
roughly 10 cars is
repairing you know if there are five six
you know service adviser who estimate
that repair and if you show the same car
same extent car to five estimators they
will estimate it
differently and the same car if you look
the estimation going to a different
insurance company you will also see a
different logic of cutting down the cost
not approving it on individual vincon
fancies so is that ecosystem
matching is that EX stand dig uh we have
attained So my answer is that is where
it's a something uh for which I'm very
very personally thankful to fada who
have aligned these stakeholders together
and this should be a starting point how
when we have a vision to become a
developed country how we mature on these
aspect how can be more transparent and
once we'll be more transparent we look
the integrities other ecosystem will
align the help together to ensure the
right you know succession we have to
sustain together yeah thank you Mr s uh
yeah shik I'll just need to add one so
VI you said uh different stakeholders
are there uh in fact uh at Mahindra I
think we have Mees in which the
estimation goes very fast so there is no
doubt about it wherein you know uh X
person or Y person giving a estimate or
somebody else giving the you know
information when OEM has set a standard
that's the place where the you know the
change is coming when you're saying we
are going towards developed country yes
we are going towards that thank you
thank you for that input withas uh I
think uh one thought that came from your
and a feed forward for us at fada is
that one stakeholder is missing in this
panel is a surveyor because he's one key
person who also plays a important C uh
true you know taking this forward from
Mr tiwari and Mr sah I would like to ask
this to the insurance uh
Representatives uh see many times uh
repair and replacement is a very big
Challenge and can we not look at uh you
know looking at the age of vehicle and
uh uh also now most of the Em are
supplying us child paths where you know
it is always demanded by the customer
that I want it to be replaced then a
repair if we can sort of create a
balance and how we can do that as
rightly again said by having uh the
right uh estimation tools uh
also probably this is an age of AI where
we can use these tools with AI to you
know come up with the right estimation
we all have database another thing to
that is uh uh this was started during Co
times there were uh video and uh I'm say
you were doing uh uh video calls and
looking at estimations I think go digit
is continuing to do that but others have
stopped doing this so your views on the
settlement process and how this can be
uh you know improved and get a better
customer experience create a comfort for
the dealer to execute this your views
you want to add something yeah
yeah so uh so here you know if you
really look at repair and replacement I
think uh the thing here is that what the
ideal case is that whatever is
repairable should be repaired and what
is replaceable should be replaced uh
obviously the customer satisfaction is
primary and vehicle safety cannot be
compromised but these are like more like
The Guiding principles but if you really
see and like you rightly said uh if the
estimation process um is is refined
properly if the estimate is very legible
and uh is detailed I think this entire
debate of what is repaired what is
replaced will get cut down to a great
extent then comes the communication part
of it um whether or not the insurance
company or the surveyor is communicating
uh properly to the customer and is there
a reverse communication with the dealer
as well I think these things in a
combination will lead to a situation
where there will be less friction and we
should also understand that by getting
into more repairs um it is also
environment friendly uh because you know
that's one responsibility all of us have
uh the plastic parts specifically uh if
it if they're repairable they should be
repaired because the replacement
obviously uh you know has wider
repercussions but at the the end of it
it is uh about striking a fine balance
without creating customer friction and I
think a lot of the organizations are
working towards that uh nothing can be
perfect on ground friction will continue
but I think if all of us as stakeholders
are committed to really follow some
guiding principles this will actually
get achieved and with more and more
technology coming in uh I think the
estimation process and the loss
assessment is uh is becoming key um and
there is a larger piece which obviously
can sound controversial because the
premium is only as much and all costs
including remuneration and claims come
out of it so so everybody has to be
judicious in the price um and obviously
the claims have to be paid uh a customer
uh uh is not at fault uh if the
insurance premium uh keeps getting
lowered or keeps getting increased you
know somebody has to communicate why is
the reason so so I think that's where it
is the digital the the video you
continue and a lot of other so what
merits did you see there uh in terms of
in the uh you know
going online service yes so so actually
this brings a lot of efficiency uh but
if you really see um I would still say
that there are lot of elements where we
as an organization still would uh you
know pursue a physical survey and this
has to be related to let's say close
proximity or you know we feel that there
are some underwriting lapses but then
those cases are stray very few but yes
it brings in a lot of efficiency the
communication is very fast and
everything is like black and white so I
think there is lot of buying from the
dealer fraternity per se because at the
end of it the car actually goes to the
garage of the dealer U and if the dealer
is not buying this obviously the
customer obviously will get influenced
there your views
Ro sh I think you said Co yeah Co helped
it to searge I think most of the
insurance companies had the online video
survey uh much before the co also uh the
acceptance from the dealership
fraternity was very less and Co helped
to increase the adoptability of that uh
platform uh if you ask to talk about
specifically to us as an organization we
hit the rate of around 74 75% of our
survey happening online U every
technology comes with its own positives
as well as negatives and U any
technology today uh we have all the
smartphones right we have so many social
media apps and other apps and it can be
misused similarly the apps technology
which we have built for uh ensuring
there's a better customer service we
have seen instances of it being misused
and hence that is the resistance which
is now coming from the insurance company
to completely promote keep promoting it
and if you look at it it's not stopped
right we invested a lot of money to
develop that software and be using it
and having a parallely a huge uh human
man Force to continue to uh lead that in
survey doesn't make any economic sense
for us but I think it's where we will
request the uh the dealership fraternity
to come and start using it judiciously
and if you use it judiciously we as an
insurance company will always love to
have a technological solution rather
than anything which is human
dependent thank you uh Mr Dei your views
on the same and you think uh a
collaboration with the insurance
companies and the oems to develop such
uh
technology for supporting this could
help us okay yes uh see uh we were
talking about repair replace and then we
are talking about the modern tools that
we should bring out so if you look at
that uh as other panelists said
definitely we have to give the best
service to our customers whether it is
repair if repair is has can be uh done
it has to be done if placement has to be
made it has to be made now regarding the
technology aspect as an organization we
are also thinking of we have already
come out with a AI based app and uh we
doing it uh but then we also believe
that it has to be on a hybrid mode uh
definitely for smaller claims now if you
look at the majority of our claims
almost 60 to 70% comes below 50,000 that
is a very uh you know small amount so
these are small claims which can be
settled very quickly by the insurance
company so again estimate uh it has to
be you know properly made and then uh
the survey also we find that surveyor is
there at the earliest so through this
app uh and also we have to understand
that machine learning and uh AI that we
talk about it's a very nent stage
especially in our country the accuracy
of that it's all uh you know uh a lot of
improvement has to come at that stage so
we are looking at all these aspects uh
how technology can help us but the again
uh the end uh result should be that the
customer has to be uh you know he has to
be happy that customer Delight has to
happen at the end of the day uh so we
also look at faster claim settlement
through all these Technologies did I
answer you or yes so I think this is a
journey that we all have to travel
together yes right uh another important
Point most dealers today are
uh uh you know dodging with or you know
facing is a umbrella policy as a whole
for the dealership itself uh may it be
the showrooms we invest a lot in our
showrooms and in our workshops and uh
similarly uh beyond the showrooms it's
it's the stocks that we carry the demo
cars the cars that are there with us for
repairs uh then uh pick up and drop for
our
customers and even you know the cars
that are there for repairs many times
we've seen that uh we've taken it out
for just after repairs for a test drive
and coming back there are some
incidences or losses uh that come in
there so there is not a single umbrella
policy uh for a dealership per se uh
don't you think now it's a high time
with almost
23,000 dealers uh over 23,000 dealers in
the country today this is a great
opportunity for insurance companies to
come up with something like this your
views ma'am yes yes definitely see when
we talk about an umbrella policy uh what
we mean is a policy which encompasses
all those risk that a particular
dealership or showroom is uh facing uh
you know one thing we have to understand
with the new product regulations that
have come in I has given us totally a
free hand to come up with any product
that the insurance company can uh
earlier you know the process of filing
it was uh file and use then it came
became use and file and now that is also
not uh entirely taken away so the uh as
insurers we do have a total free hand to
come out with the product the way we
want and our customer customer wants so
there is always a scope for discussion
and it can be there is absolutely Al
nothing that hinders uh the such a
product and already if you ask me there
are such package policies for various
other sectors if you look at petroleum
uh dealers we do have a package policy
so here we have to identify what are the
risk that is associated with a
dealership definitely your showroom your
um vehicles with trade certificates then
your Transit uh vehicle Transit from the
uh OEM to your dealership there are so
many risk associated with your with all
the dealerships definitely we can always
offer a bundle policy or an umbrella
policy as you would call it thank you uh
Atul what are the challenges that you
see in such a policy where where are
where as insurance company you see the
concerns and how uh probably you can
create advisory for the dealerships so
that they can uh while a policy like
this is is created and you can we can
save uh our Premium cost there so uh if
you really see uh you know about
designing a product so product design is
really not a concern I think it is the
underwriting uh and the risk which which
has to be insured at times it causes
some amount of friction with the
underwriter so so basically while the
coverages are all available in the
market to design and umbrella policy
also can happen but I think the best way
to approach this is that um insurance
companies need to to individually look
at uh you know the risk they want to
ensure and obviously there has to be a
price against each risk and uh if you
really look at the Indian Market on the
property side and some of the things
related to stock and all I think the
premium is disproportionate uh to the
risk perception but what happens
typically is that these are uh these are
the premiums which get accumulated over
a period of time and then there are
events like Chennai floods or some large
events which are natcat and that's where
the liability arises so I think from a
customer standpoint and here the
customer will be dealer one needs to
understand that some amount of Premium
will have to be incurred and at times it
can look at as a steep cost but if you
really look back at least only 3 4 years
from now uh looking back areas which
never had floods are having floods u a
lot of inundation cases storms and
Cyclones are coming Thrice four times a
year I think this is the time where one
needs to let go of those uh you know uh
I would say judgment calls that I don't
need this insurance uh as long as there
is a price to it and there is a price to
it U I think that these coverages are
very very uh simple to stitch and
purchase but somebody has to be patient
with it because uh in one year one might
feel that you know I have incurred so
much of cost but no claims but then
these are the events uh which nobody
wants to happen but they're happening as
we speak thank you thank you uh Rohit
your views in the same thing but also if
you can you know talk about the new age
uh places where Fidelity cyber crime and
uh you know with the new age where
payments are coming as UPI or people you
know connecting and taking money out of
our accounts or the customers being
fleed or some other uh liabilities that
could come to a dealership where you
think uh we can get insured and
Safeguard
ourselves def def itely it can be I
think today anything other than life can
be covered by a general insurance right
that's it's called it's called a
non-life insurance you name it and it
can be insured uh yes there are risks
associated with it and asul was
mentioning any risk you want to cover
comes at a price and a lot of times it
happens that it never happened in my
case I never felt there's a claim which
I have uh incurred right and hence why I
should pay right I think we need to come
into the ecosystem is changing a lot
right today what is uh used as a
technology is not anywhere relevant in 6
months one year down the line right and
today if you look at from the insurance
company we have cyber insurance as a
product right both for corporate as well
as for our individuals right so
obviously we Market the product but all
these products comes at a price and
that's I believe uh the awareness about
these products is very low and the
people really think it's an expense and
not as a protection I think that's very
important for us to realize that it's a
protection and it may happen once in 5
years it may happen once in 10 years but
if it happens and you don't have an
insurance then it wipes out everything
and hence um paying that amount is much
more important uh rather than saying
that I want to take that insurance but I
want to negotiate the pricing to a level
and that is the only reason why today
insurance companies don't underwrite
those because it finally when a need
comes we say yes the entire discussion
moves to the pricing and where the
people are not willing to
pay well said I think uh the scope for a
dealership uh insurance is very very
vast and as I said earlier with the
volume of this I'm sure the insurance
companies will find substance and uh
quality uh your views vikas on such a
policy and if it is stitched together uh
I'm sure lot of the financers here would
also since they have already funded
either the stocks or the dealership as
such would want to safeguard their
interest also so what are your views uh
on traic so uh if I have to tell you our
experience on this uh we have been
dealing with lot of dealers in which uh
we have some experience in uh doing
dealer package policy we had a vertical
and then we we had run this business as
a business exclusive business so uh when
you make a package like this dealer
package policy there are lot of you know
parts to it whether it's plate glass
fire and you know internal vehicle
within
your custody and then uh then you have
other Manpower related you have health
insurance also uh Group Health and there
are so many things which are involved in
this so if you have to study one has to
actually study the all all the all the
uh risk which are involved while
insuring this policy so when we are
ensuring this policy at that time uh the
information which has to be provided has
to be provided very clearly because
going ahead you know when uh uh I in
fact I align with roit and Atul also
here that at the time of claim if you
start taking policy then it does not
work so at the time of taking the policy
the information has to be G given very
clearly and that was the experience with
which you know we say that uh uh these
dealer package policies are extremely
good if the information is right at this
at the Inception and then of course the
claims at the time of claims you
definitely need the
documents uh some experience towards
that documents had been you know uh uh
uh it was different because uh there
have been past experiences based on
which we have to learn and we have to
move ahead so as a product dealer
package policies are very good and
extremely necessary for any dealership
so we have to actually go for it and
thank you I think we are also almost
running out of time uh I would like to
thank the panelist for their their
wonderful inputs I think uh it's very
clear yeah uh I would like uh anybody
who has a question yes
N I
think so thank you masarik I think
you've done a wonderful job terms of
engaging with the insurance companies
and even with the repairers and their
point of view on
I think where we are missing the point
is that insurance is a fiduciary
relationship with the customer with the
insured we promis to give back the
vehicle in the same condition in which
we insured it so when it comes to repair
and
replace specifically Vehicles which are
less than a year old imagine a customer
who's taken a brand new vehicle gets
dented and you say it's repairable we
will repair it and not replace it are we
being fair to the customer my first
question my second question is about the
umbrella
policy so while a lot of packaged
policies have been designed and given to
dealers but when we actually get into a
claim situation there is so much of fine
print so much of fine print
that the surveyor or the investigator
whoever he might be looks for all the
reasons why the claim should not be paid
instead of why the claim should be
paid my final question is on the number
of Investigations which are now getting
triggered just because of the value of
the claim the prices of vehicles have
gone above roof I mean if you look at
just pre-o and covid it's a 40% increase
in prices of vehicles and anything which
is coming into six figures and
investigation is ordered and
investigation can take anywhere from 1
week to a month for the investigator to
give a
report what happens to me as a dealer
because one of my productive Bay has got
blocked because the investigator is not
giving a report and I'm not able to
deliver the vehicle to the customer so
these three questions are are number
ones lot more but these three questions
to each of the insurance
companies who likes to go first
thank you sir so uh I'll just maybe give
few points and uh if you look at repair
versus replacement uh completely take
your point I myself I'm a car Enthusiast
so if something happens to my car ideal
situation will be that I would want
everything replaced but we need to
understand how the entire business
operates and and you understand it much
more better because you would be an
entrepreneur yourself uh whatever is
like I said you know uh whatever is
repairable has to be compulsorily
repaired because there is an element of
Premium to claims and the idea is not to
idea should not be to harass any
customer but the customer expectations
have to be managed and I think this can
get managed if the right parts are
repaired uh which are repairable and one
which compromises the safety or the
authenticity of the vehicle should be
replaced as simple as that but I think
where the friction occurs and this
friction is typically I would say in
about 2 to 5% of the cases is where the
customer expectation the dealer
expectation and the insurance company
expectation doesn't really meet so I
think on the go uh this actually I
cannot give a black and a white answer
but I think uh if you look at if I can
talk of my personal experience uh we
would say that you know maximum cases or
in fact almost all the cases wherever
there is a replacement U necessary I
think those are honored but at the same
time take your point point you know
those frictions definitely exist and I
think this is something to be fair will
continue because you cannot arrive at an
ideal situation so so that's Point
number one uh if you look at uh the
investigation element what you just
pointed out in claims uh we must also
see that what is triggering the
investigations while some companies
might get into this piece uh quite often
some company one might perceive that you
know nobody's really investigating but
that's not the case investigations get
triggered in in cases of legal liability
third party liability some swapping of
documents like DL swapping of vehicles
and these are like real-time issues
these are happening and I think
investigations get triggered because of
that but again how many cases do we
really see which get into investigation
so if I can tell you as an insurer uh
unless there is a third party claim or
unless there is a very uh acute case of
you know pre-existing damages multiple
damages and the cause of loss not
matching with the vehicle condition I
think these cases form less than 1 and a
half or maybe maximum 2% of the total
claims reported and this is where the
investigation piece gets triggered but
that also is subjective you know uh like
the basic things like document swapping
and all they are like today the
Integrations are available uh with the
government agencies and these are quite
prompt but the larger pieces obviously
get into a entangled kind of a
conversation so these do get stressed so
so these are my views maybe Rohit if you
want to add ma yeah yes uh I would like
to answer the first question that is
repair or replace and especially you
were talking about a vehicle Which is
less than one year so see here there is
a basic concept of principle of
Indemnity that is one of the basic
contracts of any insur so we will never
uh say no to a part that has to be
replaced I I think as an insurer I have
very clear on that if a part has to be
replaced it will be done it will be
replac but if it is repair if it is
repairable then definitely it has to be
repaired too see we cannot and in this
context I would also like to talk about
since you raised this question uh we had
a discussion on the diminishing margins
see as an insurance company let me be
very clear when I say that if when I
receive 100 rupees premium we should
also look at the uh outgo that is
happening on an average
for as far as the insurance industry is
concerned I would say when we receive
100 rupees premium almost 80 to 85
rupees I very conservative here if you
look at a public sector company it would
be much more but let us on an industry
average it is 80 to 85 rupees goes out
to the garages around 20 uh% now that
the eom regulations have come almost 30%
goes out 30 rupees goes out
our intermediary or procurement cost and
then there is the overheads so if you
look at that I'm so sorry to say it so
plainly uh we the margins are so very
very less now that doesn't reflect on
the customer service at all when we see
a customer and uh again coming back to
your first point if it has to be
repaired we will uh definitely have to
uh see that it is repaired but I don't
know as I don't think as an insurer we
have ever told that a part which had to
be replaced uh you know we uh say that
it should be repaired or anything like
that that is my answer to your first
question on investigations again we
never investigate a claim unless it is
required uh someone was talking about
close proximity claims that is accidents
happening just you know immediately
after taking the policy or it could be
theft claim or uh again it would be a
major loss where we uh whatever whether
major or minor where we had a doubt
regarding the cost of loss you know
these are areas where we may appoint an
investigator and uh investigator and
definitely we see that the reports come
fast uh also taking that queue I think
uh going forward we will see that the
investigation reports happen quite
fastly but the thing is we do have to
investigate at times uh so that is
something which we cannot avoid all
together uh but again I'm repeating that
the number of Investigations uh we do is
very very uh rare or minuscule compared
to the total number of claims that we
handle so just a counter just a small
counter uh our experience is that almost
95% of the cases which are investigated
finally get cleared finally get cleared
yes so if that is the
history just the amount of claim can
that be a trigger for investigation
because it is impacting both the
dealership and more than the dealership
it is impacting the customer so can that
be a trigger point is what I think needs
discussion I don't need an answer but it
definitely needs consideration I would
like to repeat that the percentage of uh
claims for investig are done done as far
as my experience goes it is very very
very
small I think I just add nikun sir you
have given the opportunity you know by
bringing up this point why repair do
replace now make a product like that why
not make a product like that that there
is no repairing only replacement will
happen there's a pricing to that take
that
price I think uh one last question
please yeah hi uh just to ask my
question quickly uh this is about the
cashless agreement we have as dealers
all of us as dealers have got cashless
agreement with various insurance
companies now C when we do the cashless
agreement it it covers each and every
Point generally it is one-sided
but but it covers the points to the
extent that in case after do any anomaly
or any incorrect is found in the
customers
documents the claims can be
recalled my point here is that this
should be done all the investigation the
checking dealer is not responsible for
that dealer is a facilitator deer is a
service provider this should be done
prior to releasing of the do once the do
is released and the vehicle is
delivered such Clauses are a deterent
this is part A Part B there is no
payment act defined in the
agreements if the margin of insurers is
going
down the point is it is a known point
the margin on repairs from a dealership
side is also going down it is not
increasing that's a fact
secondly there is no provision of any
interested sect on delayed payments
there is no provision of any penalties
on delayed payments or inordinately
delayed payments if the vehicle has
deliver been delivered after do there
could be large payments also many huge
repair bills also and in the over volume
of dealership this is a huge working
capital which gets
blocked secondly uh I would also urge
fada if uh we could uh get the model D
agreement on the cashless side also so I
would like to have I would like to to
have your insights on these points and
way and suggestions for Way
Forward I'll do do
it I think uh uh R said I think any
insurance company would not want its
customers to suffer um and every point
of time we would want the customers to
have a good experience and if you look
at it uh when is the time when the
customer actually have an experience
dealing with the insurance companies
only at the time of claim right the
policies sold by each one of you thanks
to you we get the premium and that's the
only place where we interact with the
customers and as an insurance company
would never like that experience to be
bad but there are enough of instances
where we've seen uh there have been
frauds now we we investigate our
investigation percentage of the cases
are very less right and as you said if
95% is is also passed after the
investigation that 5% claims which we
save on that is our significant value
which impacts the pnl of insurance
company and if I'm saying that if for
example hypothetically we start paying
that in the end it's finally our own pnl
right we get 100 rupes we have to manage
100 rupees and if we start setting those
claims at some place we will have to cut
it right be it on the commission side or
we have to increase the premium right
and then everyone who's in the Lin of
business as you guys are we are on in
the lines of business we are all
supposed to manage our pnl right uh if
for example new vehicles you said they
should not be there but you also know
that in the new vehicles there's a huge
uh uh commercials which are involved on
that side right it impacts our p in that
way itself right any insurance company
would want uh as Atul said we all are
ourselves owner of a car right we would
want our car to go to a garage and the
paths to be replaced but it comes at a
cost and is the customer is the Indian
market today ready to pay that price
right all know is the price War which
happens on the motor side right it's
finally we have to manage our pnl if we
have to let go of something from this we
have has to be compensated from
somewhere
else I think uh let's end this and very
good so you have given us a good point
we'll have that model dealer agreement
done soon and uh we'll circulate it
among all the insurance companies thank
you and one point uh nikle you said on
the uh dealer policy uh package policy I
think this is with IA Den notifying and
now all insurance companies can set up
their
uh package policies customized package
policies I think this is an Challenge
and an uh opportunity for all the
insurance companies uh with 23,000
dealers and growing and the vast network
of dealerships across the
country much absolutely so this is a
great opportunity with such an organized
industry I think this is something that
first mve Advantage will be great to
jump on thank you everyone thank you
thank you very
[Applause]
much well thank you so much to all our
panelist and our moderator for such a
thunderous panel discussion well now is
the time for the
felicitation and I would like to invite
on stage Mr John K Paul to felicitate Mr
Prine tiwari can we have huge huge
thunderous applauses everyone out
[Music]
here next I would like to invite on
stage Mr harendra Kumar to felicitate Mr
Rohit Daga
[Music]
can we have warm claps everyone out here
thank you so
much next I would like to invite on
stage Mr hitendra nanavati to felicitate
miss svi sriharan ner can we have huge
huge
claps and next I would like to invite on
stage Mr goind P Mayar to felicitate Mr
vikas medata can we have warm claps
everyone out
[Music]
here now I would like to request Mr
sharik sha to felicitate Mr VI sahai
let's not stop the
claps next I would like to invite on
stage Mr wenat Raju gooli to felicitate
Mr Atul
mea let's give it up with lots of claps
everyone out here thank you so much
[Music]
well thank you so much and I would
request all of you to gather for a group
picture
[Music]
port